export const QuestionList = [
  {
    question: "What was the name of the first IBM computer?",
    options: ["a) IBM 3030", "b) IBM 4532", "c) IBM 5112", "d) IBM 5150"],
    answer: "d",
  },

  {
    question: "Which company invented the USB port?",
    options: ["a) Intel Corporations", "b) IBM", "c) HP", "d) APPLE"],
    answer: "a",
  },

  {
    question: "What type of application is MS- Word ?",
    options: [
      "a) Operating System",
      "b) Word Processor",
      "c) Word Typing",
      "d) Word Play",
    ],

    answer: "b",
  },
  {
    question:
      "'Firefox', 'Chrome', and 'Safari' are what type of computer software?",
    options: ["a) Internet", "b) Gaming", "c) Web Browser", "d) Hardware"],
    answer: "c",
  },

  {
    question:
      "In what type of application we can add slides, text, images, graphics, and videos?",
    options: [
      "a) Gaming Software",
      "b) Web Browser",
      "c) Word Processing",
      "d) Presentation Software",
    ],
    answer: "d",
  },
  {
    question: "'.xls' is a file extension used in which application?",
    options: ["a) Ms Excel", "b) Ms Access", "c) Ms Powerpoint", "d) Ms Word"],
    answer: "a",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What application programs are used to organize, store, and modify data in computers?",

    options: [
      "a) Ms Excel",
      "b) Database management Systems",
      "c) Programmers",
      "d) Data Collectors",
    ],
    answer: "b",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Which programs are used to translate high- level language into a machine language code?",
    options: [
      "a) Compilation trackers",
      "b) Mysql Trackers",
      "c) Programming language translators, assemblers, compilers, and interpreters",
      "d) Programming Assemblers",
    ],
    answer: "c",
  },

  {
    question:
      "'Adobe Photoshop' and 'PaintShop Pro' are examples of which type of applications?",

    options: [
      "a) Design Software",
      "b) Photo Software",
      "c) Programming Software",
      "d) Graphics Software",
    ],
    answer: "d",
  },

  {
    question:
      "What type of applications are available to users on a trial basis only for a limited period of time?",
    options: ["a) Freeware", "b) Shareware", "c) Trialware", "d) Paidware"],
    answer: "b",
  },

  {
    question:
      "What type of computer applications have an intersecting area called cells and can perform calculations with formulas and functions?",

    options: ["a) Spreadsheet", "b) Rows", "c) Columns", "d) Tettrash"],
    answer: "a",
  },

  {
    question:
      "'VLC media player' and 'Windows media player' are what type of programs?",

    options: ["a) Multimedia", "b) Video", "c) Netsyce", "d) Gameplayer"],
    answer: "a",
  },

  {
    question:
      "What type of applications are available with a source code to modify and add features to it? ",

    options: [
      "a) FreeSource Applications",
      "b) OpenSource Applications",
      "c) Sharesource Applications",
      "d) Available source application",
    ],
    answer: "b",
  },

  {
    question:
      "A computer which is smaller than a laptop and about the size of a textbook is: ",
    options: [
      "a) Textbook Computer",
      "b) Notebook Computer",
      "c) Tablet Computer",
      "d) Ipad Computer",
    ],
    answer: "b",
  },

  {
    question:
      "A small input device with one or more buttons used as for painting or drawing is: ",

    options: ["a) Drawing Pad", "b) Mouse", "c) Keyboard", "d) Drawing key"],
    answer: "b",
  },

  {
    question:
      "The simultaneous execution of two or more programs in one computer is called:",

    options: [
      "a) Multi-tasking",
      "b) Double-tasking",
      "c) More-Taksing",
      "d) Tasking Tasking",
    ],
    answer: "a",
  },

  {
    question: "PASCAL was developed by:",

    options: [
      "a) Nikky Sinctis",
      "b) Ninola Dennis",
      "c) Niklaus Wirth",
      "d) Nikolas Whittr",
    ],
    answer: "c",
  },

  {
    question:
      "The computer with multiple processors with shared memory space is known as: ",

    options: [
      "a) Double Processor System",
      "b) Share Processing Memory",
      "c) Multi-Processor System",
      "d) Double Shared Processor",
    ],
    answer: "c",
  },
  {
    question:
      "A security method that identifies a specific authorized user of a computer system, by a unique string of character that user types as an identification code is",

    options: ["a) Pin", "b) Security", "c) Password", "d) Authentication"],

    answer: "c",
  },
  {
    question: "Who is currently the CEO of Microsoft?",
    options: [
      "a) Larry Page",
      "b) Jack Dorsey",
      "c) Satya Nadella",
      "d) Renault Audiger",
    ],

    answer: "c",
  },
];
